I'm sorry if this sounds terrible, but...
抱歉 我这么问可能没教养，但是…
aren't you a little developed in years to be running up a giant mountain?
您这年纪去爬大山 是不是太成熟了点？
"Developed," now that's certainly one way of putting it.
"成熟" 这说法倒蛮合适的
Well, I've been up there, you know. - Really? - Mm-hm.
那什么 我倒是上去过。  - 真的啊？- 嗯
I made it to 26,000 feet before we had to turn back.
在队伍被迫下撤之前 我爬到了8千米的高度
- Really? - Mm-hm.
- 真的啊？- 嗯
What was it like?
什么感觉？
Cold... mostly.
冷的很… 这是主要的感觉
During the day, the sky is more black than blue.
在白天 天空是黑黝黝的蓝色…
There's not enough air to reflect the sunlight.
因为没有足够的空气来折射阳光
But at night, you've never seen so many stars.
但到了晚上…从来也没见过那么多星星
Seems like they're just out of reach, and so bright.
有些星星熠熠闪亮 似乎伸手可及
They're like little holes in the floor of heaven.
像是透光的小洞 洞的那头是天堂
- Did you hear it? - Hear what?
- 那你听见了没有？- 听见什么？
I read an account of a man who made it to the summit...
我读过一本登顶者写的书
and standing there at the top of the world...
书里说他站在世界之巅…
he experienced this profound silence.
感受到一种深邃的寂静
It was like all sound just fell away.
就像所有声音都消失了一样
And that's when he heard it.
就在那时 他听见了…
What?
听见了什么？
The sound of the mountain.
山的声音
He said it was like he heard the voice of God.
他说那感觉 就像聆听上帝的话语
I've never done this before.
我以前从没这么做过
That sounds like such a cliche, but...
这话听上去很老套 但是…
but I have a room upstairs.
…我在楼上有个房间
Well, that's...
呃 那个…
I mean...
我是说…
I...
我…
I appreciate that.
我很感激
But you see...
但是…
She's a very lucky woman.
她太幸运了
Well, I rather think I'm the lucky one.
我觉得幸运的人应该是我
Good for you.
真为你高兴